Ten-Second Summary

I have over a decade of professional experience as a Linux sysadmin, in both commercial and government settings. I've designed, deployed, and managed large complex systems. Automation, proper processes, and documentation ensures they're reliable and maintainable.

Employment experience

Enterprise Linux administrator – NSW Dept. of Education

Aug 2015 - Present

- Deployed automated patching for 1000+ RHEL hosts, reducing hands-on effort by an order of magnitude.
- Developed data gathering and analysis tools to aid internal reporting processes.
- Automated RPM packaging for internally maintained software, deployed to servers via RedHat Satellite.
- Performed risk assessment and provided recommendations as part of change management procedures.
- Partnered with other business units to design, develop, and deploy new systems.
- Scripted and automated many common procedures to improve efficiency and reduce errors.
- Updated large amounts of documentation and processes to bring them to an auditable standard.
- Wrote onboarding docs for new staff members, reducing the time needed for face-to-face training.

R&D Engineer - Anchor

Aug 2013 – Aug 2015

- Worked as part of a small internal team on tooling and efficiency measures to support sysadmins.
- Languages and tools were chosen for their suitability to the task. This broadly included Python, Ruby and Haskell for app code, and Postgres, Redis, Elasticsearch, Ceph, and Druid for the backend technologies.
- Wrote UMAD, a knowledge search engine spanning disparate sources of information, including our wiki, support ticketing system, domain registrations, and CRM.
- Machiavelli, a graphing interface for Nagios metrics.
- Vaultaire and associated microservices, a time-series database for large-scale storage of monitoring metrics, built on top of the Ceph datastore.
- Used CoreOS images and Docker containers to deploy our apps onto our in-house Openstack cluster.
- Jenkins and Travis CI for packaging and deployment to private repos, in addition to comprehensive testing.

Technical writer - Anchor

Nov 2011 - Aug 2013

- Wrote and edited thousands of pages of internal procedures, guides, and documentation, supporting every facet of the business, targeted for different audiences as required.
- Managed deadlines presented by multiple teams, ensuring documentation was consistently delivered on-time.
- Published 200+ articles on the blog, written to a specifically tech-savvy audience, to entertain and enlighten.
- Developed all new training modules for new staff to get them up to speed and productive as soon as possible.
- Initiated and maintained a new public-facing knowledgebase for customers.

Senior systems administrator – Anchor

Apr 2007 - Nov 2011

- Upgraded internal monitoring systems to implement escalation of alerts.
- Introduced Puppet for automation of customer server builds, replacing cfengine.
- Mentored new staff, working closely to get them settled in and up to speed.
- Performed forensic analysis and reporting following security breaches.
- Developed processes for rapid virtualisation of physical servers, helping reduce operating costs.

Knowledge and experience

Operating Systems Extensive experience with Linux, primarily Redhat and Debian. Exposure

to Windows 7/8/10, Server 2008 and 2012, some Exchange, some OS X

Languages Heavy use of Python, shell, Perl, PHP, C, some Ruby and Java, Haskell and

category theory

Databases PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite, Redis, basic administration of MSSQL

Networking Architecture and design, capacity planning, addressing and subnetting,

routing and associated protocols, high availability, debugging, performance,

IPsec and OpenVPN, IPv6, firewalls

Security Policy, risk assessment, reporting, auditing, analysis, best practice, crypto

Automation Puppet, automated OS installation with tools such as Kickstart and d-i,

scripting with core unix utilities, etc.

Webapps Common LAMP stack, nginx, WSGI, Rails via Thin/Unicorn/Passenger,

Tomcat

Scalability & clustering HAproxy, Corosync and Pacemaker, DRBD

People I am first and foremost a good listener. I communicate clearly and effectively

in any medium, and can explain complex concepts to others regardless of

their level of familiarity.

Education

Bachelor of Science (Computer Science) University of New South Wales 2002 - 2006